#### Contact

piuskariuki19@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/pius-kariuki-1796041b4 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Django

Recoil

Adobe Illustrator

#### Certifications

Front-End Web Development with React

Google Analytics Individual Qualification

# Pius Kariuki

Full Stack Engineer (React/Vue/Node/Django/Mongo/Express) Nairobi, Nairobi County, Kenya

### Summary

Pius is a proficient Software Engineer who utilizes tools like Vue JS and React for 3+ years. With a great eye for design and good problem solving skills, he has been able to provide software solutions to client problems. He enjoys the process of building a software platform to life but is able to deliver projects under strict deadlines.

Pius also has experience building Rest and Graph APIs using technologies like Node JS, Express JS and Django.

### Experience

Welz

Senior Frontend Developer November 2022 - Present (10 months)

Manhattan, New York, United States

Worked with the development team at Welz to create and maintain their current software platform.

#### Responsibilities

- -Scaling the platform to accommodate more insurance company options.
- -Coordinated with all software engineers and designers.
- -Improved appointment scheduling by enforcing uniformity across time zones.
- -Increased the customers base by providing more payment options.
- -Maintained the platform dashboard.

Xeron Clinical Laboratories Senior Frontend Developer March 2023 - May 2023 (3 months)

New York, United States

Joined the Xeron development team and revamped their current platform's outlook.

Responsibilities

- -Brought the set designed specs to life by implementing elegant interactive interfaces.
- -Improved the internet presence of the organization by including more information like google maps directions to their clinics and a service catalog for each of them

### +MEDRITE Urgent Care Senior Frontend Developer January 2023 - March 2023 (3 months) New York, United States

Worked at Medrite Urgent care to improve their existing platform.

### Responsibilities

- -Added a preregistration module to the current medrite platform
- -Implemented design specs. into interactive interfaces.
- -Handled API integrations and web testing

### Speed Dates Kenya Full Stack Engineer June 2022 - January 2023 (8 months) Nairobi Kenya

Worked as the sole developer for A-List-Events(formerly speed dates).

#### Responsibilities

- -Coming up with a design for their platform.
- -Implementing the design into interactive interfaces.
- -Persisting data in a MongoDB and implementing business logic in an Express JS and GraphQL environment.
- -Building an admin panel for the client.

Reggy Codas(Software Consultancy)
Full Stack Engineer
October 2021 - June 2022 (9 months)
Nakuru, Kenya

Joined the Reggy team to work on various client projects.

#### Responsibilities

- -Built an e-commerce platform with real-time chat, video and interaction capabilities.
- -Designed and implemented interactive interfaces for various client projects.

-Built APIs to enforce business logic and persist data mostly on MongoDB databases.

## Education

**Egerton University** 

Bachelor of computer science , Computer Science  $\cdot$  (January 2017 - April 2022)